so ganellin is a medication that is an
analog for genotropin releasing hormone
or G&R what that does is essentially it
mimics what the hypothalamus
releases prior to getting to the
pituitary and telling it to release
luteinizing
hormone if your pituitary has good
function then it may and I say may
because not always but it may work the
problem is that because the anterior
pituitary which sits in the front of
your brain is responsible for
leutinizing hormone and anyone who's had
any level of TBI which is traumatic
brain injury or any sort of head trauma
like a concussion and a lot of guys have
whether it be football MMA you know car
accident military whatever the case is
if you've ever suffered a concussion
then presumably there's going to be some
level of damage to the interior
pituitary and it may throw off the
genotropin signaling so luteinizing
hormone levels and this can also be
impacted by drugs alcohol uh overthe
counter medication and poor sleep as
well as stress levels all of these
factors which now we're starting to
Encompass the masses as far as the
population goes right now the more are
these things we name the more people are
probably saying hey that sounds like me
your luteinizing level hormones are
going to be low so stimulating a
pituitary that is lagging or already
fatigued is like kicking a dead horse
it's not going to do a whole lot so
releasing more G&R which is granat Trope
and what it does is granatell excuse me
is it mimics G&R it simply tells the
pituitary to work harder but telling a
failed gland to work harder is not
really going to do a whole lot what HCG
does is it mimics luteinizing hormone it
bypasses the pituitary's need to
actually produce any gonadotropins and
it actually provide your testicles
directly with a genotropic signal called
lutenizing hormone so it is
significantly more effective because
think of getting closer to the scene of
the accident right we can't like clear
the roadway from you know two miles back
we got to be like right on top of the
problem and for more most men the
problem is the pituitary not the
hypothalamus